NOA HEYL

Pronouns: they/them

(+1) 236 777 1500 ◊ me@falkirks.com

falkirks.com ogithub.com/falkirks

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages Software & Tools Java, PHP, Node.JS, C/C++, Python, SQL

Git, Docker, web, databases, networking, DevOps

OPEN SOURCE

PocketMine Minecraft Pocket Edition server software

Created and maintained several popular plugins (eg: SimpleWarp, MineReset, and Specter) for Minecraft (PHP), totalling more than 2 million downloads since 2014. Organized community contributions on GitHub, and managed plugin development forum. Created and operated a free hostname creation service (Angular and Node.js) for Minecraft servers.

Pronouny *Personal* pronoun sharing webapp

Created, deployed and maintained since 2016 at github.com/pronouns. Built full stack app (Javascript) including database schema (MongoDB). Conducted an audit of web accessibility using the latest WCAG guidelines.

Additional open source projects are available on my Github...

EXPERIENCE

UBC Computer Science

Jan 2018 – present

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Facilitated labs for software engineering (Java) and algorithms (C++) courses. Helped instructors by preparing assignments, designing exam questions and improving class materials on an online learning platform. Consistently rated 4.9/5.0 in student evaluations of my teaching.

UBC Library May 2018 – Dec 2018

Undergraduate Academic Assistant

Assisted a senior instructor in developing an online course textbook on algorithms and data structures. Designed and adapted web simulations (**Javascript**) of data structures to improve student learning outcomes.

Girlsmarts Nov 2017 – Feb 2018

Programming Workshop Facilitator

Created learning infrastructure (**NodeJS** and **React**) for monitoring student progress in real-time. Led the facilitation and presentation of workshops to Grade 6 students.

Lord Byng Secondary Feb 2016 – Dec 2016

Software Developer

Developed an online system (**Angular** and **MongoDB**) to allow students to earn badges for community engagement. Supervised the deployment and scaling of the system as it became available to all students in the program.

EDUCATION

Planning to pursue an MSc in Computer Science starting in September 2020.

University of British Columbia (BA)

Major in Computer Science Minor in Social Justice Sept 2016 – May 2020 Overall GPA: 85.5% Computer Science GPA: 93.3%

AWARDS

- VISIER Service Award Dec 2018 Awarded by UBC Computer Science
- Student Service Award May 2018 Awarded by UBC Computer Science

- **Dean's list** Sept 2017- May 2018 Awarded by UBC for high academic standing
- Best use of React nwHacks

 Hackathon prize for an audience engagement tool